<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>can&#39;s corner</title>
    <link>https://ucan35.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on can&#39;s corner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 09:41:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ucan35.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Makefile &amp; Container Fusion</title>
      <link>https://ucan35.github.io/makefile-container-fusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 09:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ucan35.github.io/makefile-container-fusion/</guid>
      <description>Makefiles always make me feel comfortable whenever they are delivered with projects. The ease of following convention make build never ceases to amaze me. However, there is still one fear I have, system dependencies. Why don&amp;rsquo;t we get rid of that fear with fusion of makefiles and containers?
Make Make1 is a great utility to automate many task for your projects. Instead of bulky shell scripts, I very much prefer makefiles2 for their ability to divide tasks into dependent sub tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Terminal Your Home</title>
      <link>https://ucan35.github.io/making-terminal-your-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 09:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ucan35.github.io/making-terminal-your-home/</guid>
      <description>Home is where you feel comfortable and safe. It&amp;rsquo;s your place that you can organize stuff to your convention. The very same feeling with your with your terminal can empower you and increase your productivity greatly.
The reason why I prefer terminals is not because that they make you cool. While I don&amp;rsquo;t deny that they indeed make you cool, the main reason is that they provide you only the most essential data, text streams.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Containerized X11 Applications</title>
      <link>https://ucan35.github.io/containerized-x11-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 18:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ucan35.github.io/containerized-x11-applications/</guid>
      <description>Containers1 are great. They provide us means to isolate applications by leveraging Linux namespaces2. We can run any kind of application under containers, including X113 applications.
X11 applications are essentially applications with GUI&amp;rsquo;s that use X. While applications like standard Linux utilities can be easily run under containers since they tend to have minimal dependencies, X11 applications on the other hand, can be a bit more difficult to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
